

Ashish Sinha Software Engineer

ashish.sinha@saama.com

7259227950

Pune, India

15 April, 1993

linkedin.com/in/ashishsinha-150493

Multitalented BI and RPA Developer with 4.5 years experience in IT software industry. Demonstrated excellent skills developing ETL processes and automating tasks using UiPath RPA tool, PowerShell and Python. True team player with strengths in adaptability and accuracy.

WORK EXPERIENCE

ETL/RPA Developer Saama Technologies/BeiGene

10/2020 - Present Pune

Focused on developing molecularly targeted and immuno-oncology drug candidates for the treatment of cancer

- Developed and automated the ETL processes to load data into Synapse using Azure Data Factory and Databricks, leveraging the PowerShell and Python scripts to communicate with Azure services from on premises file system.
- Developed/Optimized workflows for Quality Analytics using UiPath and Python.
- Automated processes to move file to or from FTP server and to upload/download files from SharePoint using UiPath RPA.
- Automated processes to download file from mail and process them to Database using UiPath RPA.
- Automated sending job notification with run details of each process thus minimized the monitoring and debugging time.

Contact: Shweta Barhate (Team Lead) - shweta.barhate@saama.com

RPA Developer

Saama Technologies/Portola Pharmaceuticals

07/2019 - 09/2020

Pune

Researches, develops and commercializes drugs focusing primarily on treatment of thrombosis and hematological malignancies.

Achievements/Tasks

- Pull data from Salesforce through dynamic queries and integrate it with SQL Server using UiPath thus saving Monthly recurring \$100 licensing cost.
- Integrated with BOX using API to upload / download files for further processing thus saving manual efforts and time.
- FTP operations were integrated by RPA eliminated Dell Boomi and saved annual recurring \$100k licensing cost.
- Automate download of Files from web portals where we login into web portals, download files, da quality checks and pass file for further processing.

Contact: Deepali Desai - deepali.desai@saama.com

Informatica Developer

Infosys Ltd./Stater

Pune

01/2017 - 12/2019 Provides mortgage services and platforms for external money lenders.

Achievements/Tasks

- Develop mappings according to client's need
- Automation of adding columns to existing's mappings using PowerShell scripts

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology SRM University/ Chennai

08/2012 - 05/2016

Courses

Electronics and Communication Engineering

SKILLS



ACHIEVEMENTS

Shining Star of the Month (08/2020)

Awarded for work on uipath and Google dialogue flow chatbots

Shining Star of the Month (01/2020)

Shining Star of the Month for automating download of files from portal and upload/download files from BOX using REST API and Box Connector in UiPath

CERTIFICATES

Machine Learning (08/2020 - Present)

Completed certification on Machine Learning from SimpliLearn.

Data Science with Python (07/2020 - Present)

Completed certification on Data Science with Python from SimpliLearn.

UiPath AI Fabric Overview (07/2020 - Present)

RPA Developer Foundation Diploma Certification (05/2020 - Present)

Completed Developer foundation certification from UiPath

UiPath Advanced RPA Developer Diploma Certification (05/2020 - Present)

Completed Advanced Developer foundation certification from UiPath.

ORGANIZATIONS

Saama Technologies (01/2019 - Present)

Software Engineer

Infosys Limited (06/2016 - 12/2019)

Senior System Engineer